<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I am Xiaohao Yang | 楊瀟豪 on xiaohao yang | 楊瀟豪</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I am Xiaohao Yang | 楊瀟豪 on xiaohao yang | 楊瀟豪</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download large-scale LiDAR data using dsmSearch</title>
      <link>/2024/03/12/dsmsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/03/12/dsmsearch/</guid>
      <description>LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) or point cloud data is useful when we are conducting high-resolution spatial analysis such as viewshed/viewscape, watershed runoff, and other analysis based on digital surface/terrain models. But collecting LiDAR data may challenge for data download and storage because the data is huge even for a median-scale area like a city. Converting a large amount of point cloud into a raster for spatial analysis could be even more computationally expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A symbiotic relationship between boba-tea shops and restaurants?</title>
      <link>/2024/03/10/boba-tea-restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/03/10/boba-tea-restaurants/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction Babo tea - &amp;ldquo;波霸奶茶&amp;rdquo; in Chinese (also known as pearl milk tea or bubble milk tea) - with its origins in Taiwan, holds particular appeal among customers interested in Asian cuisines and cultural experiences. Enjoying boba tea while waiting for a table at a restaurant or as a delightful treat after dining is a widespread practice in urban areas like Los Angeles, CA. Boba-tea shops and restaurants often serve as complementary businesses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the website with blogdown</title>
      <link>/2024/02/16/customize-the-website-with-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/02/16/customize-the-website-with-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The initial idea of building a personal website is just showcasing some of my works from design studios, I used to directly craft my HTML5 website without any framework and then handle my portfolio on platforms that provide cloud-based web development services. As I got more projects done recently, I became increasingly lazy to update my portfolio website and the price for using the cloud-based web services is incredibly expensive. So, I was looking for a more interesting way to organize my staffs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>viewscape in R</title>
      <link>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</guid>
      <description>This is an integrated tutorial about viewscape and dsmSearch. These two packages were initially one before getting published because I thought it would be cool if one can just specify a geographical area without DSM/DEM to compute a viewshed(s). This has been explained the purpose of making the dsmSearch, which was two functions for searching and downloading point cloud data via API.&#xA;Of course, viewscape is not designed for just computing the viewshed even if this is the core of the package.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABOUT</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Me News Publications Peer review Resume This website Contact [Me] I am a big fan of R (even if I have to use Python and Javascript much more than it for my work) and cellular automata! I am a coder [] of [design ] ], [art ] ], [games ] ], and [R tools ] ]. I am working several projects in terms of LLMs. I am trying to do everything I think is interesting even if I need to overcome a lot of challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPUTATIONAL ARTWORKS</title>
      <link>/artworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/artworks/</guid>
      <description>Coding art is fun. I got one self-motivated project (the first one) and several course-based projects.&#xA;Pop-upColor Pop-upColor is an generative art project I started in 2021. Initially, I just played with celular autometa to create some 3D patterns with Python in Rhinoceros. I thought it would be interesting to make a more interactive web application to customize and generate these patterns. So, I used Three.js to write this project. [project website ] [source ]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DESIGNS</title>
      <link>/designworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/designworks/</guid>
      <description>AR/VR Mobile App Computation Urban As a generative designer, I code 3D with RhinoScriptSyntax in Rhino. As an interaction designer and frontend engineer, I design application, prototype user interface, and deploy APPs on different devices. I am trying to do something interesting/funny/hopefully useful with XR (VR/AR).&#xA;VR Phillips House A VR game that provides an unforgettable experience in Phillips House. Two key experiences: Menu includes two modes: building sequence and visit tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAMES</title>
      <link>/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/games/</guid>
      <description>I like video games (PC/SWITCH/GameBoy/Mobile games&amp;hellip;) and have spent a lot of time on it. I almost get rid of PC games after I switched to Mac from Windows (while spending more time on Nintendo Switch and Gameboy). I was trying to play and make some VR games for cardboard and Oculus quest 2, but I am not a fan of VR right now because dizziness just made me so uncomfortable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESEARCH</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Urban science Social media Climate change Mapping Perceived Safety Around Bus Stops In Detroit Using Crowdsourced Street Views The concept of social infrastructure takes into account the physical places and organizations that shape the way people interact. This project is rooted in the idea that bus stops are not merely transit locations but pivotal social infrastructures that contribute significantly to the urban social fabric. Perceived safety is a critical aspect of an accessible public transport system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TOOLS</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>I make either useful or useless tools for research (fun)&#xA;streetscape A collection of functions to search and download street view imagery and to extract, quantify, and visualize visual features. Moreover, there are functions provided to generate Qualtrics survey in TXT format with street views.&#xA;quickPWCR A collection of functions for constructing large pairwise comparisons and rating them using the Elo rating system with supporting parallel processing. The method of random sample pairs is based on Reservoir Sampling.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
