<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xiaohaoyang</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on xiaohaoyang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>viewscape in R</title>
      <link>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</guid>
      <description>This is an integrated tutorial about viewscape and dsmSearch. These two packages were initially one before getting published because I thought it would be cool if one can just specify a geographical area without DSM/DEM to compute a viewshed(s). This has been explained the purpose of making the dsmSearch, which was two functions for searching and downloading point cloud data via API.&#xA;Of course, viewscape is not designed for computing the viewshed even if this is the core of the package.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 02:22:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is Xiaohao Yang&amp;rsquo;s website. I built it with blogdown. My education background is initially rooted in landscape architecture (7 years) and now overlaps with Data Sciense and Human-computer Interaction (since 2019).&#xA;I usually fill (ruin) my schedule with my work (interests). Deadline always help me focus on priority.&#xA;I am a big fan of R! I am a coder of design, art, games, and tools. I am a researcher on soundscape and landscape at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/artworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/artworks/</guid>
      <description>Coding art is fun. I got one self-motivated project (the first one) and several course-based projects.&#xA;Pop-upColor Pop-upColor is an generative art project I started in 2021. Initially, I just played with celular autometa to create some interesting 3D patterns with Python in Rhinoceros&#xA;Yo-yoCap Yo-yoCap explores the enhancement of yo-yo performance art through the application of motion capture technology, aiming to create a more dynamic and interactive audio-visual spectacle. By utilizing 2D motion capture with OpenCV and transmitting data to MAX/MSP for processing, this research investigates how real-time tracking of yo-yo movements can alter background music and visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description> Education 2014-2018 South China Agricultural University (SCAU), China - Bachelor of Engineering in Landscape Architecture - Graduation Thesis: Salty Agriculture in the Pearl River Delta - selected for exhibition by Symposium on Chinese Landscape Architecture Education 2018 2019-2022 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/designworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/designworks/</guid>
      <description>Maybe I would do some games in R one day.&#xA;randomStairBranch This is a simple scipt developed with RhinoScriptSyntax in Python. A simple agent method was implemented.&#xA;terrain </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/games/</guid>
      <description>I like video games (PC/XBOX/SWITCH/Mobile games&amp;hellip;) and have spent a lot of time on it. I almost get rid of PC games after I switch to Mac from Windows. Thanks to Mac&amp;rsquo;s graphic card. Now, I am working on a game series SillySimilation.&#xA;SillySimilation There are three games in the SillySimilation series. Each of them tells a story about survival. The environment has been extremely simplified and accelerated in games. There is always some trade-off in the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Chen, C., Xia, Y., &amp;amp; Yang, X. (2020). Resilience Strategies to Impacts of Sea Level Rise on the Agricultural Areas in Nansha District of Guangzhou. Landscape Architecture Frontiers, 8(3), 10-25. https://doi.org/10.15302/J-LAF-1-020027&#xA;CHEN Chongxian, YANG Xiaohao, XIA Yu*. Impact of Sea Level Rise on Coastal Wetland Landscape Based on Sea Level Affecting Marshes Model[J]. Landscape Architecture, 2019, 26(9): 75-82. DOI: 10.14085/j.fjyl.2019.09.0075.08&#xA;Chen, C., Luo, W., Kang, N., Li, H., Yang, X., &amp;amp; Xia, Y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>I make either useful or useless tools for research (fun)&#xA;viewscape Viewshed-based viewscape analysis supports a range of scientific domains, including urban planning and ecosystem service research, focusing on enhancing well-being benefits. However, most viewshed tools and applications are proprietary and may not be accessible to all. Here, we introduce the open-source R package viewscape created for reproducible calculations of visual landscape metrics within the R environment.&#xA;dsmSearch The package dsmSearch offers functions for retrieving high-resolution Digital Surface Models (DSM) and Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data, providing a toolkit to collect remote sensing data effectively for research and analysis in fields such as ecology, geography, urban planning, and forestry.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
