<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on xiaohao yang | 楊瀟豪</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on xiaohao yang | 楊瀟豪</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download large-scale LiDAR data using dsmSearch</title>
      <link>/2024/03/12/dsmsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/03/12/dsmsearch/</guid>
      <description>LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) or point cloud data is useful when we are conducting high-resolution spatial analysis such as viewshed/viewscape, watershed runoff, and other analysis based on digital surface/terrain models. But collecting LiDAR data may challenge for data download and storage because the data is huge even for a median-scale area like a city. Converting a large amount of point cloud into a raster for spatial analysis could be even more computationally expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A symbiotic relationship between boba-tea shops and restaurants?</title>
      <link>/2024/03/10/boba-tea-restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/03/10/boba-tea-restaurants/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction Babo tea - &amp;ldquo;波霸奶茶&amp;rdquo; in Chinese (also known as pearl milk tea or bubble milk tea) - with its origins in Taiwan, holds particular appeal among customers interested in Asian cuisines and cultural experiences. Enjoying boba tea while waiting for a table at a restaurant or as a delightful treat after dining is a widespread practice in urban areas like Los Angeles, CA. Boba-tea shops and restaurants often serve as complementary businesses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the website with blogdown</title>
      <link>/2024/02/16/customize-the-website-with-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/02/16/customize-the-website-with-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The initial idea of building a personal website is just showcasing some of my works from design studios, I used to directly craft my HTML5 website without any framework and then handle my portfolio on platforms that provide cloud-based web development services. As I got more projects done recently, I became increasingly lazy to update my portfolio website and the price for using the cloud-based web services is incredibly expensive. So, I was looking for a more interesting way to organize my staffs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>viewscape in R</title>
      <link>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/02/13/viewscape/</guid>
      <description>This is an integrated tutorial about viewscape and dsmSearch. These two packages were initially one before getting published because I thought it would be cool if one can just specify a geographical area without DSM/DEM to compute a viewshed(s). This has been explained the purpose of making the dsmSearch, which was two functions for searching and downloading point cloud data via API.&#xA;Of course, viewscape is not designed for just computing the viewshed even if this is the core of the package.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
